- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[goofy music]
[愚蠢的音乐]
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Attention, shoppers:
- 购物者请注意：
We've got a SpongeBob
on Aisle 6.
我们有海绵宝宝
在 6 号过道上。
[all screaming, shouting]
[所有人尖叫，喊叫]
[both screaming]
- Make a sharp left!
[两人尖叫]
- 向左急转！
[both babbling]
[两人都胡言乱语]
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
- We're here!
- [straining]
- 我们到了！
- [紧张]
I still don't understand
why you had me wear
我还是不明白
你为什么让我穿
a blindfold.
- Oh, um, I didn't want you
一个眼罩。
- 哦，嗯，我不想要你
to get anything
in your eyes.
得到任何东西
在你眼里。
See?
看？
♪ ♪
[babbling]
[胡说]
- [exclaims, laughs]
- [惊呼，大笑]
[impish music]
[顽皮的音乐]
- Okay, thanks, buddy.
- 好的，谢谢，伙计。
I'm going
to my club meeting now.
我要去
现在参加我的俱乐部会议。
- What's your club, hmm?
[giggles]
- 你的俱乐部是什么，嗯？
[咯咯笑]
- Uh, it's the
Empty Head Society.
- 呃，这是
空头协会。
Eh, it's a place
where guys like me
呃，是一个地方
像我这样的人在哪里
can give their
"powerful intellects"
可以给他们的
“强大的智力”
a much-needed rest.
- Whoa!
急需的休息。
- 哇！
I'd love to rest my intellect.
我很想让我的智力得到休息。
Can I join?
- Sure!
我可以加入吗？
- 当然！
Anyone can join.
任何人都可以加入。
It's exclusive.
这是独一无二的。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
[straining]
- Oh, that's not how
[紧张]
-哦，不是这样的
you open it.
你打开它。
You have to step on
你必须踩
the automatic doormat.
自动门垫。
- Hmm.
- 唔。
- Ding!
- 叮！
♪ ♪
[goofy exclamation]
[愚蠢的感叹]
- Oh!
- 哦！
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
[goofy music]
[愚蠢的音乐]
- [goofy laughter]
- [傻笑]
- Wow.
- 哇。
They do seem
blissfully brainless.
他们确实看起来
幸福无脑。
[exclaiming]
- Oh, oh, hold it!
[惊呼]
-哦，哦，坚持住！
You have to check
your smart thingy
你必须检查
你聪明的东西
at the door.
在门口。
♪ ♪
- [clucking]
- [咯咯笑]
[babbling]
[胡说]
- Ah!
- 啊！
[straining]
[紧张]
[goofy babbling]
[胡言乱语]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Ugh.
- 呃。
[both babbling]
[两人都胡言乱语]
- Hello, numbskull.
- Hiya, dodo!
- 你好，笨蛋。
- 嗨，渡渡鸟！
- Shall we do
the Empty Head handshake?
-我们可以吗
空头握手？
- Okay!
- 好的！
♪ ♪
[both babbling]
[两人都胡言乱语]
♪ ♪
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- [screams]
What was that?
- [尖叫]
那是什么？
- The signal
for the meeting to start.
- 信号
会议开始。
Come on.
[all chattering]
快点。
[大家都在喋喋不休]
[both babbling]
[两人都胡言乱语]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
- [hollering]
- [喊叫]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[triumphant fanfare]
[凯旋的号角]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[microphone feedback]
[麦克风反馈]
Good, I see everyone's
in their assigned places.
好的，我看到大家了
在他们指定的地方。
The Secretary
will now read the minutes.
秘书
现在将宣读会议纪要。
- These are the minutes.
- 这些是会议记录。
One minute, twelve minutes,
一分钟，十二分钟，
wait a minute,
give me a minute.
等一下，
给我一分钟。
- Hike!
[grunts]
- 远足！
[咕哝]
Are there any new initiates
here tonight?
有没有新的入门者
今晚在这里吗？
- [whispering]
SpongeBob, go up.
- [低语]
海绵宝宝，上去吧。
You always wanted
to join the club.
你一直想要
加入俱乐部。
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[babbles, laughs]
[胡言乱语，大笑]
- Hmm, are you sure
you're, uh, brainless enough?
- 嗯，你确定吗
你够没脑子吧？
- Hmm.
[shouts]
- 唔。
[喊叫]
- Perfect!
- 完美的！
You've earned your first badge.
您已经赢得了第一枚徽章。
- [laughs weakly]
- [虚弱地笑]
- It's time to pass the jar.
- 是时候传递罐子了。
- Hmm?
- 唔？
- [babbling]
Mm!
- [胡言乱语]
嗯！
- [gargling]
- [漱口]
- [retches]
- [干呕]
[crowd groans]
[人群呻吟]
- Hmm?
Uh...
- 唔？
呃...
all: Drink! Drink! Drink!
全体：喝！喝！喝！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[whining]
[抱怨]
all: Drink! Drink! Drink!
全体：喝！喝！喝！
[gagging]
[作呕]
[belches]
[打嗝]
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
- Ugh!
- What?
- 呃！
- 什么？
You said drink!
- Ahem.
你说喝！
- 咳咳。
Lemonade?
- Huh?
柠檬水？
- 啊？
- We just save and date
the drool.
- 我们只是保存并日期
流口水。
But that was so dopey
you earned another badge!
但那太愚蠢了
您又赢得了一枚徽章！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
There!
- Ah!
那里！
- 啊！
- It's now time for us
to go out in the community
- 现在是我们的时间了
到社区去
and help the citizens...
- Ow!
并帮助公民...
- 噢！
- Of Bikini Bottom
- 比基尼下装
by doing our civic duty.
通过履行我们的公民义务。
Whatever that means.
不管那意味着什么。
- Uh, we're gonna do
some civic duty?
- 呃，我们要做
一些公民义务？
- We call it the "Nitwitting."
- 我们称之为“傻子”。
all: ♪ We're all unfit ♪
所有人：♪ 我们都不适合 ♪
♪ We must admit ♪
♪ 我们必须承认 ♪
♪ We're dumb
as a box of rocks ♪
♪ 我们是笨蛋
就像一盒石头♪
♪ But time permitting
we'll be nitwitting ♪
♪ 但时间允许的话
我们会开玩笑的 ♪
♪ Has anyone seen our socks? ♪
♪ 有人看到我们的袜子了吗？ ♪
- To the mini boats!
- 去迷你船！
both: To the mini boats!
两人：去迷你船！
[Richard Wagner's
"Ride of the Valkyries plays"]
[理查德·瓦格纳的
“女武神的骑行演奏”]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
- Patrick, why are we
doing this, again?
- 帕特里克，我们为什么
又做这个？
- I have no idea.
- 我不知道。
[horn tooting]
[喇叭声]
♪ ♪
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
[both gasp, scream]
[两人都喘气，尖叫]
- [shrieks]
- [尖叫]
[cart neighs]
[购物车嘶嘶声]
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
[cheerful tropical music]
【欢快的热带音乐】
- Hey, mister.
- 嘿，先生。
You dropped your ball.
你把球掉了。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[overlapping shouting]
[重叠的喊叫]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
♪ ♪
- Keep running.
- 继续跑。
I'll pace you.
我来给你配速。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- These lights could use
a smile.
- 这些灯可以使用
一个微笑。
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
♪ ♪
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
- I have a feeling
you guys are a little confused
- 我有一种感觉
你们有点困惑
about what civic duty is.
关于什么是公民义务。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
Uh, I don't think so!
呃，我不这么认为！
"Civic duty is using
your patootie."
“公民义务正在使用
你的土豆。”
[laughs, grunts]
[笑声，咕哝声]
No confusion there!
[grunts]
那里没有混乱！
[咕哝]
[tires squeal]
[轮胎吱吱声]
[exasperated music]
[愤怒的音乐]
♪ ♪
Why would people throw
their stinky garbage
为什么人们会扔
他们的臭垃圾
in these beautiful cans?
在这些漂亮的罐子里？
- Hmm?
- 唔？
Maybe their pockets
were already full.
也许他们的口袋
已经满了。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
"Pockets full"?
“口袋满了”？
I can clearly see you're not
as brainless as us.
我可以清楚地看到你不是
和我们一样无脑。
- Aww...
- I can't see anything!
- 哇...
- 我什么也看不见！
[sighs]
Oh well.
[叹气]
哦，好吧。
I guess I'm just not
Empty Head material.
我想我只是不
空头材料。
Well, bye, buddy.
好吧，再见，伙计。
- My name's "Buddy" now?
- 我现在的名字是“Buddy”？
[lighthearted music]
[轻松的音乐]
both chanting: Buddy! Buddy!
两人都高呼：伙计！伙伴！
Buddy!
伙伴！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Well, that's funny.
嗯，这很有趣。
I seem to be lost.
我似乎迷路了。
Oh, I'll figure it out.
哦，我会想办法的。
I still got some life
in the ol' brain stem.
我还有一点生命
在脑干中。
[electrical zapping]
[电击]
♪ ♪
[babbling]
[胡说]
What's a brain stem?
什么是脑干？
I know!
我知道！
I'll just walk backwards,
and that should get me back
我只会向后走
那应该能让我回来
to the beginning of the day.
到一天的开始。
[speaking backwards]
[倒着说]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
I'm even more lost-er
than I was before-er.
我更迷失了er
比我以前-呃。
[gasps]
[喘气]
Oh, I will direct asking--
噢，我就直接问——
[grunts]
Ask directions.
[咕哝]
问路。
[seal barks]
[海豹吠叫]
♪ ♪
Excuse me, large lady.
对不起，大女士。
I'm a widdle girl
who's misplaced herself.
我是一个小提琴女孩
谁把自己放错了地方。
Can you help find me?
你能帮忙找到我吗？
[lisping]
I'm pretty.
[口齿不清]
我很漂亮。
- Weirdo!
- Ow!
- 怪人！
- 噢！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Well, that didn't
come out right.
- 嗯，那没有
出来吧。
[whines]
[哀鸣]
[downtrodden music]
[压抑的音乐]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
♪ ♪
[babbling]
[胡说]
Oh, I've forgotten how to sit.
哦，我忘记怎么坐了。
- [chuckles]
Obviously not
- [轻笑]
显然不是
the sharpest tool in the--
最锋利的工具——
the tool thing.
工具的事情。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[gasps]
[喘气]
Ooh.
- Oh, there you are!
哦。
- 哦，你来了！
You forgot
your thinking thingy.
你忘了
你的思想。
I wasn't sure which one
was yours, buddy.
我不确定是哪一个
是你的，伙计。
- Uh, now my name's "Buddy"?
- No, duh.
- 呃，现在我的名字是“Buddy”？
- 不，呃。
That's my name!
- [groans]
那是我的名字！
- [呻吟]
- I think.
- 我认为。
- [grunts]
No, not mine.
- [咕哝]
不，不是我的。
Wrong brain.
脑子错了。
[babbles]
Oh, bad brain.
[胡言乱语]
哎呀，脑子不好使。
Oh, I guess I'll take
this stupid one.
哦，我想我会采取
这个蠢货。
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
- Hmm.
- 唔。
Hmm...
唔...
[growling]
- [babbling]
[咆哮]
- [胡言乱语]
- Try saying "I'm ready."
- 尝试说“我准备好了”。
- Slime heady!
- 史莱姆令人兴奋！
Uh, dime Betty!
呃，一毛钱贝蒂！
- [growling]
- [babbling]
- [咆哮]
- [胡言乱语]
[grunts]
Spaghetti!
[咕哝]
意大利面！
I'm sweaty!
我满头大汗了！
I'm all wetty!
我都湿透了！
♪ ♪
[both babbling]
[两人都胡言乱语]
- I'm ready.
- 我准备好了。
[gasps]
I'm ready!
[喘气]
我准备好了！
I'm ready!
High-five!
- Yeah!
高五！
- 是的！
- [babbles, laughs]
- [胡言乱语，大笑]
Patrick, I know you
and the Empty Head Society
帕特里克，我认识你
和空头协会
mean well, but man,
we sure messed up a lot
意思是好的，但是伙计，
我们确实搞砸了很多
of things in town today.
今天城里的事情。
So I'm gonna reverse
all the damage that we did
所以我要逆转
我们造成的所有伤害
during the Nitwitting!
在闲聊期间！
- Hey, you'd better hurry
- 嘿，你最好快点
because you're getting smaller!
因为你越来越小了！
What a guy.
真是个家伙啊。
Hmm?
唔？
[babbling]
[胡说]
Nothing like a good sit
in a chair.
没有什么比好好坐一坐更好的了
在椅子上。
Ah.
啊。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Oh, that's weird.
哦，这很奇怪。
[impish music]
[顽皮的音乐]
Everything's already back
to normal.
一切都已经回来了
至正常。
What?
什么？
Hmm.
唔。
[babbling]
[胡说]
Oh.
哦。
Hmm.
Well, it's still a mess
唔。
好吧，还是一团糟
over here.
在这里。
♪ ♪
[gasps]
Sandy?
[喘气]
桑迪？
You cleaned everything up?
- Of course, SpongeBob.
你把所有东西都清理干净了吗？
- 当然，海绵宝宝。
I belong to a club
called FEHMA.
我属于一个俱乐部
称为FEHMA。
That stands for "Fix
the Empty Head's Mess Again."
这代表“修复
空脑袋又乱了。”
Our civic duty is repairing
the mayhem
我们的公民义务是修复
混乱
that the Empty Heads cause
every month.
空脑袋造成的
每个月。
You got some gunk on your tie.
- Yeah, they're badges.
你的领带上沾了一些东西。
- 是的，它们是徽章。
[munching]
- Hey, SpongeBob.
[咀嚼]
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
How would you like
to join FEHMA?
你想要怎样
加入FEHMA？
- No thanks.
- 不，谢谢。
After giving my brain
a vacation, I need a rest.
献出我的大脑后
放假了，我需要休息。
both: Huh?
- Uh-oh!
两人：啊？
- 呃哦！
Speaking of "brain vacation."
说到“大脑假期”。
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
[horn tooting]
[喇叭声]
all: ♪ We must admit ♪
所有人：♪ 我们必须承认 ♪
♪ We're dumb as a box
of rocks ♪
♪ 我们就像一个盒子一样愚蠢
岩石♪
♪ But time permitting ♪
♪ 但如果时间允许 ♪
♪ We'll be nitwitting ♪
♪ 我们会开玩笑 ♪
- ♪ Has anyone seen my socks? ♪
[grunts]
- ♪ 有人看到我的袜子了吗？ ♪
[咕哝]
♪ ♪